You are not alone.
Man of Steel is a action, adventure, science
fiction film directed by Zack Snyder.
A young boy learns that he has extraordinary powers and is not of this earth.
As a young man, he journeys to discover where he came
from and what he was sent here to do.
But the hero in him must emerge if he is to save the world from
annihilation and become the symbol of hope for all mankind.
Clark Kent / Superman / Kal-El, played by Henry Cavill.
Lois Lane, played by Amy Adams.
Jor-El, played by Russell Crowe.
General Zod, played by Michael Shannon.
Jonathan Kent, played by Kevin Costner.
Perry White, played by Laurence Fishburne.
Man of Steel is a 2013 superhero film based on the DC character Superman.
Directed by Zack Snyder and written by David S.
Goyer, who developed the story with producer Christopher Nolan, it is the first film in the DC Extended
Universe (DCEU), and a reboot of the Superman film series, depicting the character's origin story.
Henry Cavill stars as Superman, alongside Amy Adams, Michael Shannon, Kevin
Costner, Diane Lane, Laurence Fishburne, and Russell Crowe.
In the film, Clark Kent learns that he is a superpowered alien from the planet Krypton and assumes the role of
mankind's protector as Superman, making the choice to face General Zod and stop him from destroying humanity.
Development began in 2008 when Warner Bros.
took pitches from comic book writers, screenwriters, and
directors, opting to reboot the franchise.
In 2009, a court ruling resulted in Jerry Siegel's family recapturing
the rights to Superman's origins and Siegel's copyright.
The decision stated that Warner Bros.
did not owe the families additional royalties from previous films, but if they did not begin production on a Superman film
by 2011, then the Shuster and Siegel estates would be able to sue for lost revenue on an unproduced film.
Nolan pitched Goyer's idea after a story discussion on The Dark Knight Rises,
and Snyder was hired as the film's director in October 2010.
Principal photography began in August 2011 in West Chicago,
Illinois, before moving to Vancouver and Plano, Illinois.
Man of Steel premiered in the Alice Tully Hall in New York City on
June 10, 2013, and was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures in the United States on June 14.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, and was a commercial success, grossing $670 million
worldwide on a budget of $225–258 million, becoming the ninth-highest-grossing film of 2013.
A sequel, Batman v Superman: Dawn of Justice, was released in 2016.
A further reboot, Superman, the first film in the DC Universe (DCU), was
released in 2025, and stars David Corenswet as the title character.
The film explores themes of saving the world,
flying, hope, superhero, based on comic.
The tone is thought_provoking.